Eduard Fernando Martínez González

 $\begin{tabular}{lll} E-mail: & ef.martinezg@uniandes.edu.co\\ Web-page: & https://eduard-martinez.github.io\\ \end{tabular}$

GitHub: eduard-martinez

CURRENT POSITIONS

Departament of Economics, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia.

2019 - Adjunct professor - Statistical & R Programming Workshop Seminar.

2021 - Adjunct professor - Big Data and Machine Learning for Real Estate.

2022 - Teaching Assitance - Big Data and Machine Learning for Applied Economics.

EDUCATION

	Departament of Economics,	Universidad	de los	Andes,	${\bf Colombia.}$
1	DID ' E				

2018 - Currently | PhD. in Economics. 2022 | M.Sc in Economics.

Departament of Economics, Universidad del Magdalena, Colombia.

2017 B.A. In Economics.

FIELDS OF INTERESTS

Crime Economics, Urban Economics, Public Policy, Applied Econometrics, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

PREVIOUS RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

2021 - 2022 Departament of Economics and Finance, Universidad EAFIT, Colombia.

Research Analyst at Centro de Investigaciones Económicas y Financieras (CIEF).

Prof. Santiago Tobón.

2019 - 2020 Departament of Economics, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia.

Research Assistant at Centro de Estudios de Desarrollo Económico (CEDE)

Prof. Maria del Pilar López.

2018 - 2019 Departament of Economics, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia.

Research Analyst at Centro de Estudios sobre Seguridad y Drogas (CESED).

Prof. Michael Weintraub.

2016 - 2017 | Central Bank of Colombia.

Research Assistant at Centro de Estudios Económicos Regionales (CEER) Researcher Leonardo Bonilla Mejía.

2015 - 2016 | Departament of Economics, Universidad del Magdalena, Colombia.

Research Assistant at Grupo de Análisis en Ciencias Económicas (GACE) Prof. Etna Bayona.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

- 2021 Departament of Economics and Finance, Universidad EAFIT, Colombia.

 Adjunct professor: Workshop at R for Applied Economics.
- 2021 Universidad Piloto de Colombia, Colombia. Adjunct professor: Workshop at Geostatistics.
- 2019 2020 | Fundación Ideas para la Paz (FIP), Colombia.

 Research Analyst: Grupo Dinámicas del Conflicto y Negociaciones de Paz.
- 2019 2020 | Departament of Economics, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia.
 Guest Lecturer: Module of Economics in Constitución y Democracia.

PUBLICATIONS

Bayona-Velásquez, Etna M.; Erazo-Ortiz, Dayanna S. y Martínez-González, Eduard F. (2018). Fomento a la innovación en la industria manufacturera de Colombia: Un análisis cuantitativo para 2013-2014. *Dimensión Empresarial*, 17(1), 15-28.

Bonilla-Mejía, L. y Martínez-González, E., (2017). Educación Escolar para la Inclusión y la Transformación Social en el Caribe Colombiano. Revista del Banco de la República.

WORKING PAPERS

Economics Shocks and Crime: Evidence From Colombia. Available here.

Motorcycle Restrictions and Crime in Colombia. Documento CEDE No. 27, Available at SSRN. (With Michael Weintraub, Leonardo Bonilla-Mejía and Juan Pablo Meza).

Payroll taxes, wage rigidities and youth unemployment: Evidence from colombian labor market. Avaliabe here. (With Danilo E. Aristizabal).

WORK IN PROGRESS

Coca, Glyphosate and the balloon effect. (with Hernando Zuleta and María del Pilar López-Uribe)

Land Property Rights in Drug Policy: Evidence from the Formalizar para Substitution program in Colombia. (with María del Pilar López-Uribe, Juan Carlos Muñoz-Mora, Ana Pirela de los Rios and Carolina Castro)

Incomplete Peace and Cocaine Dutch Disease. (With Lucas Marín Llanes, Manuel Fernández and María Alejandra Vélez)

Measuring the spatial displacement of illicit crops in Colombia. (With María Alejandra Vélez, Hernando Zuleta and Lucas Marín Llanes)

SOFTWARE

Skills: R (advanced), STATA, QGIS, ARCGIS, HTML (intermediate), Python (basic).

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Citizenship: Colombian

Languages: Spanish (native), English (fluent).